WHEN LIFE GIVES YOU TANGERINES
DAUGHTER OF YANG GWAN-SIK AND OH AE-SUN
YANG GEUM-MYEONG! ACCEPTED TO SNU!
'88 SEOUL OLYMPICS CELEBRATION
ADVANCED CITIZENS! ADVANCED STREETS!
So what if it's the Olympics for you?
We have the Olympics here every day too.
Survival was their Olympics.
No, it's not what you think.
It's not like that, so…
They fought through their own grand
yet cruel Olympics every single time.
Please just leave!
…without medals, pensions, or retirement.
Why are you flipping them?
What does flipping our stalls have to do
with your Olympics?
Did conches and sauries protest
against the Olympics?
Did they block the roads?
Come on, seriously!
How many times have I told you?
The Olympic torch is coming through here!
Americans will be watching this on TV.
Should we just show them
this mess of fish intestines
and a fishy stench?
Do their televisions have noses
attached to them?
The government has told us
to clean up things that lack aesthetics.
The government!
Aesthetics?
You're taking away our livelihood
to impress some people
on the other side of the world?
What kind of dog crap is that?
Is that how Americans do things?
Taking even a beggar's bowl?
For God's sake.
Why don't you fight for the country
instead of selling sauries?
We should accept a little loss
for the greater good.
You're always nitpicking
every tiny detail!
Someone greased your palm, didn't they?
What, because I don't have money?
How much did they pay you
for the town's blood, sweat, and tears?
How much?
And you call yourself our chief?
Did you major in saying ten things
after hearing one?
-What?
-It's next September.
The torch will pass through here briefly.
We live hand to mouth.
You're cutting off our source of income!
What kind of law is that?
What do you know about the law?
Do you even know anything?
Oh Ae-sun!
Where is Ae-sun?
Our deputy chief
is a high school graduate!
She dropped out of high school.
-What do you mean "graduate"?
-But she went to high school!
Where is our deputy chief?
-Ae-sun!
-Our deputy chief is the smartest!
-Why are you looking for her?
She wouldn't know what to say!
Why can't I sell my sauries
just because the nation is celebrating?
Why do your sauries even matter now?
If North Korea wants to ruin the Olympics
and open the Mount Kumgang dam,
all of Seoul will be flooded.
They say that even the 63 SQUARE
will be submerged.
Do you keep up with current affairs?
Do you understand the greater good?
Are sauries really more important
than the great…ness of history?
Of course they're important!
-They're important!
-So frustrating.
You think a rebellion happens
for no reason?
Even a dog will crap all over and leave
if you tip over its food bowl!
Do you want some of ours?
-Let go!
-Do you want some?
Ae-sun!
She's here. Here's Ae-sun.
There you are.
Hey!
Hey. Deputy.
Hey! Deputy!
Is she the crap you mentioned? Is she?
You better get up.
This is a silent outcry…
What did you say?
Lashed by the scourge
Of the bitter season…
If you're embarrassed, just get up.
Don't try anything.
If you choose to leave…
Hey, call a forklift!
Let it roll over me!
Hey, this is a gangster,
not a high school graduate.
Taking people's livelihoods away
makes you a gangster, not me.
What did you just say?
Roll over me.
Seriously, what's wrong with you?
Roll over me!
Just do as you're told!
I said roll over me!
Roll over me!
Hey, what happened to our Literary Girl?
What do you mean?
Life happened, that's what.
Goddamn it!
For goodness' sake!
Hey, Bu Sang-gil!
You betrayed the people's trust,
and you'll definitely pay the price.
Politics is like the wind, you know?
Rumors are spreading like wildfire
that Ae-sun will be
the next fishing co-op chief.
Come on, I have no interest in politics.
I think you'll run for office.
People like her always end up
running for office.
This election will be
between a stooge and a freedom fighter.
That spineless traitor.
If we side with that treacherous stooge,
they'll screw us over
right under our noses.
So what if he's the chief.
How dare he call a person "deputy"!
Deputy Chief is the official title,
and he's always like, "Deputy!"
"Hey, Deputy!" That's how he addresses me.
She never liked being a deputy.
If a dog can be the chief, why can't you?
Let's make a chief
out of one of our haenyeo crew.
I really have no interest in politics!
You won't let your darling
Gwan-sik's dream come true?
What's gotten into you?
Our captain must be
campaigning for someone.
What's this for?
Who do you want us to vote for?
Captain Yang,
now that you've paid me off, speak up.
Well…
I'm not saying this because she's my wife.
But Ae-sun was class president
back in the day.
I saw it myself.
I can honestly say
that I've never met anyone
as smart as Ae-sun.
Have you ever been smart enough
to become class president?
Let's be frank between us.
Do you actually want Ae-sun
to be the chief?
Your wife would be
the first female chief of Dodong-ri.
What does that make you?
A real man should have some pride.
Yes, she'd be the first, but so would I.
If Ae-sun becomes the first female chief,
I'd be the first husband of a chief.
Pride is even better
when you earn it without effort.
That's enough, okay?
You're making the rest of us men
look like trash.
Our captain has dreams
that are very different from ours.
So, this is a brand-new item.
I'm going to do all of it.
I'll be the chief of the fishing co-op.
I'm also going to be
the president five times.
What do you want to become?
Don't even ask him!
The First Lady.
So…
What is it? First Lady.
I think they put… real bananas in those.
Premium bananas.
You drank it all.
Hey, man.
This banana milk is nothing.
That tightwad is buying pork for everyone.
Who in the world doesn't like pork?
SALT-GRILLED PORK
Not just any pig.
Jeju Black pig, you know?
Jeju Black pig.
Premium Jeju Black pig.
Give each table an extra portion
that looks like a double.
We only serve Jeju Black pig.
I really don't have any ulterior motive.
Look, I have no shortage
of money or honor.
I only ever have one concern on my mind.
How can I give our co-op members
one more thing to eat?
"How can I find one more thing to give?"
Listen, you should pay attention
while you eat.
You squeeze all of us into this tiny place
just so we can nibble on the pork.
Finish your plate,
then you can order more.
I don't think you'd vote for me,
but you're here.
You should bribe generously.
What a stingy briber.
So, anyway,
Oh Ae-sun appeared out of nowhere,
but I hail from Dodong-ri.
I am the rightful heir to the--
I asked for a soda ages ago.
Not everyone can hold a big title, right?
We need to carefully examine
the candidates' backgrounds
and any family issues they may have.
What problems does the deputy chief have?
Gwan-sik is receiving a commendation.
Do you have one?
It's a plaque of appreciation,
not a commendation.
I could easily get
more than a dozen of those.
-You know--
-But you don't have any.
Have you ever saved anyone from drowning?
Stop cutting me off already!
Learn to listen when others are talking.
These women talk about what they want
every chance they get.
How about you? Why act like
you didn't hear me ask for a soda?
As you all know,
that family isn't exactly
a great example for others.
They ran away from home at 18
and had a daughter.
She's a student at SNU.
Not their second child.
There's no need to talk about
someone else's kid, but…
Never mind. I shouldn't.
Then don't. And get me a soda!
If you sow beans, you'll only reap beans.
Being a nutjob is hereditary, you know?
DODONG-RI FISHING CO-OP DEPUTY CHIEF
MOTHER OF YANG EUN-MYEONG
DODONG-RI FISHING CO-OP CHIEF
Wait, have you been to the salon?
Take this off.
How many student leaders' moms are coming?
All of them?
But wait, you were the PE leader?
Why you?
That's funny.
The other moms are gonna flip out
when they get here,
asking how your sister
got into Seoul National University
and what the secret was. Goodness me.
Someone's excited.
It's at 4:00, right? Let's go.
-Mom.
-Am I a bit early?
-Mother!
-Should I go to the faculty room?
There aren't any other moms.
Why not? You said they invited
all the leaders' mothers to come.
It's just you.
Why?
Hello, sir.
No need to come in. Let's go out.
Pardon me?
Let's go outside.
My car is now an Onata?
The Chinese teacher's car is now Pon!
Our dear Eun-myeong
is getting all the kids into university.
So that's it, huh? Anyone gets in
if you get them the initials?
Is that how your sister got in?
He doesn't just give them away.
He takes them off and sells them.
Ma'am, this is a very serious matter.
The principal's car is now a Tellar!
I've been teaching for about 20 years.
Yang Eun-myeong is the first to ever turn
a teacher's car into an Onata!
I'm sorry.
Your son seems like he's here to work.
I heard he's good with his hands.
He cuts a set of ten bus tickets
into eleven
and makes a profit of 50 won.
The coin game's being played out there?
That'll be Eun-myeong, then!
Is school some kind of gambling den?
Is he running a business here?
Is he a teacher or something?
Why would a student come to school
to earn a paycheck?
I'm sorry.
Did you give your daughter your all
but go hands-off with your son?
Do you know what kind of kids
your son hangs out with?
Keep your distance.
Don't even talk to me.
You said it was just a leaders' meeting!
Who told you to make money?
Why don't you study? Why focus on money?
I never felt embarrassed
coming to school for your sister.
But now, I can't hold my head up!
Stop hitting that!
What's wrong with you?
What did I ever do to you?
I told you to do half
of what your sister did, didn't I?
I raised both of you the same way.
Do half as well
so you can become the chief?
Being a nutjob is in the genes,
so I'll be in your way.
Don't listen to what people say!
-I hate Bu Sang-gil.
-You're embarrassed by me, aren't you?
You only want to be
Geum-myeong's mom, huh?
Not everyone in her family is a nutjob.
But education isn't everything in life.
Whose daughter is she, after all?
Sure, she's up in Seoul,
but she's just going to end up
a dating queen too.
CELEBRATING DIRECT PRESIDENTIAL
ELECTION SYSTEM
He always picks her up these days.
Is that her boyfriend?
Is he rich or something?
Even if he is, how can a college student
drive a car like that?
Something's off about that girl.
Look at the news.
Lots of college girls work as escorts.
They get paid to go on dates
and spend time with older men.
Ju-gyeong.
Show some respect.
Is he from the US?
Is he not embarrassed?
He's opening the door for her in public.
Guys like that cut pork cutlets
for girls at restaurants.
Love is all I know
Whose child is she?
As they say, it's so blindingly obvious.
I don't even need eyes to see it.
That family never cared
about keeping boys and girls apart.
Hey, you may have bought the tree,
but that rock isn't yours, is it?
Why did you write your name
on the public property?
Think about it.
She should be grateful
to be the deputy chief,
but she has no clue.
Who does she think she is?
Hey, Captain.
Do you actually have any campaign pledges?
What?
I think you're splashing out
just to bash your opponent.
I'm not bashing anyone.
I'm just discussing morality.
Don't you realize
people have the right to know?
Don't you know?
BADA SEAFOOD HOUSE
Why would he bring your kids into this?
Shit-gil crossed the line with that one.
You fight back too.
If you keep this up,
Ae-sun's going to fight back.
Ae-sun's just holding back
because she has class.
If she really wanted to play dirty,
you wouldn't exactly come out
looking so clean either.
Sang-gil's father was the first
during the Japanese occupation.
First to surrender his Korean name
to the Japanese in Jeju.
Hold on.
There's nothing you can say about me,
even if you want to.
I'm a man
who makes donations to our government.
As for Oh Ae-sun?
I'm pretty sure
she's never given a dime to charity.
Politics is just a field
of dog crap anyway.
If you're going to roll in it,
black fur is better than white.
Who cares what fur a dog has
if it rolls around in crap?
It's just a dog with crap on it.
I'm going to win with my pledges.
Wow, Oh Ae-sun is still so noble.
You're not handing out soap.
You're not feeding them pork.
And you're not playing dirty?
Then you're going to lose.
Ae-sun, the co-op members have the right
to know Sang-gil's true colors.
He was the first to cross the line.
You might as well too.
A cocoon that doesn't break open in time
gets devoured by predators.
Only the ones that break free quickly
emerge as butterflies.
You need to learn how to open the doors
that are in your way, just like this.
In every ferry
That reaches the Oryukdo Islets
People can take turns to bad-mouth me
No matter how hard they try
They won't find a speck of dust on me
That's the worst thing about me
Try to find something on me all you want
Stop singing!
I'm not voting for you
if I lose my appetite.
Damn it!
Hey, where are my noodles?
He's always picking on his wife.
You can't even make noodles quickly.
Just walk home.
Don't get in my car. Got it?
Hey, Bu Sang-gil.
Your surname means "deputy" anyway.
It means you're the "deputy" captain
on the boat
and the "deputy" chief
for the fishing co-op.
-Hey!
-Are you voting for me or not?
Why do you always come and pick a fight?
Is it because I didn't buy you a soda?
Hey, in case you lose the election…
Why would I lose?
Do you know how much the pork
and noodles cost?
Just be content
with being the deputy chief.
Even on the Animal Quiz Show,
if the Alpha is defeated,
it will instantly become the pack Omega.
-Hey!
-"Hey"?
Did you say "hey"?
-Am I getting those noodles anytime today?
You can vote for Oh Ae-sun if you want.
FROM BU SANG-GIL, CANDIDATE 1
The Oh may be smart,
and the Bu may be lacking,
but a female chief?
Nowhere in this nation!
-No, of course not.
-A box of cigarettes each.
I wish it was always election season.
How can a gentle breeze
from the pines stop a typhoon?
Democracy? It's all about numbers.
Stick with the majority.
The chief must be the Bu!
All right!
Pour me some.
Now!
-The chief is…
-The Bu!
Lucky you.
I hope you're the chief forever.
Indecency runs in that family!
I named my daughters
Hyeon-suk for "virtuous"
and Jeong-suk for "pure."
And I
like those who are virtuous.
What a load of crap.
I am
a candidate with nothing to be ashamed of.
The thing is,
life has been so difficult for me.
We could clear out all the street stalls,
and I still wouldn't make much from it.
A real estate office in this small town
barely makes any money.
I just wanted to make a little dough
from the Olympics,
but those haenyeo are so stubborn.
For real, you know me.
-Yeah.
-I'm a softie.
Mi-suk, you know me.
I'll take care of everything.
Without a doubt,
I'm going to be the chief again.
Really?
You'd really take care of everything?
I don't need to pay you a fee or anything?
Just give me 30.
-What?
-You keep 70%. I'll take 30.
Right, I see.
Even a flea's liver should be shared.
Mi-suk, I'm Bu Sang-gil of Dodong-ri.
Mi-suk.
I don't have romance in my life,
but I do have money.
I am
just one lonely man.
There's no need to be shy around me.
I'm not shy.
No, I mean…
You think I'd help you
do all this for money?
Then what are you doing it for?
What are you looking at?
Come on.
It's the Olympics, right?
Even the Soviet Union
chose to stand hand in hand
and break down the walls.
Why don't we break down…
the wall between us?
Eat this. Your stomach will hurt.
Wait.
Mi-suk's saury just struck me
like an arrow in the heart.
Perhaps this isn't just any saury.
Is it okay to think of it
as Mi-suk's heart instead?
Yeah, sure.
Abalone?
You make everything else in the world
seem like baloney.
Just eat the shrimp.
Now you mention it,
you're making my shrimp…
You're so silly!
What? What's wrong?
You're making me really excited.
You make my heart excited. What?
You're witty. I'll give you that.
Hey, you…
came here to eat some sea squirts.
Why are you serenading my solitude?
That tickles.
Disgusting.
You're so disgusting. Seriously.
You need to learn how to open the doors
that are in your way, just like this.
Wait. What's all this…
What are you doing here? Damn it.
I was wondering
why you chose to be the stooge.
You're so disgusting
that we can't even crack open sea squirts.
What the hell are you doing here again?
Who do you think you are,
meddling in my life all the time?
This is my part-time job. So what?
While a saury struck your heart,
she was cracking open another sea squirt.
Wait, why were you eavesdropping on us?
-Why?
-Hey!
You just want to be chief so you can
massage another woman's feet, huh?
Goddamn it!
But you can't even be the chief anymore.
Why can't I be?
Why?
A stray dog runs around the neighborhood
causing all kinds of trouble.
You're just a mutt
trying to hump every woman's leg.
Hey!
We wouldn't even give
a mutt like you rotten rice.
But you still want to be chief?
Stop crapping all over town!
Goddamn it!
Hey, come on.
Do you even know what happened?
What do you know?
She said she was just getting cramps
in her toes, so--
Well, your wife's getting cramps
in her heart.
"A great example"?
The candidate's "family problems,"
you say?
It's better for a candidate's son
to be a nutjob
than for a candidate to be.
He's actually pretty clever!
So what now?
Are you going to tell people about me?
Of course we are.
We are going to
so that Ae-sun can be chief.
That's right.
Hey, you. Is that what you stand for?
"Right to know."
"Morality."
I'm not bashing anyone.
I'm just discussing morality.
Don't you realize
people have the right to know?
Isn't that what you like?
Wow, Ae-sun.
Goddamn it!
This is so silly.
CONGRATULATIONS
THE 7TH DODONG-RI CHIEF, OH AE-SUN
Oh Ae-sun!
The small ball that Ae-sun launched…
Goodness me. Look at this!
Did the school lend this to us?
They only use it once a year
for sports day.
…came back down, bursting open in half.
And Jeju had…
Chief!
…its first-ever female chief.
Chief! Chief Oh!
Yes!
-The rice cake is here.
-It's here now?
-Chief Oh, we're out of makgeolli.
-Really?
Chief Oh.
Can I have a blanket?
Yes.
Chief! The school wants to know
when you'll return the confetti ball.
It must have pulled at her heartstrings.
Many years later,
Mom joined Lim Young-woong's fan club,
and her username was "Chief Oh."
Chief!
Chief, come over here
and have a taste. Come on!
Coming!
I'm coming!
-Go ahead and take that.
-Okay.
THE 5TH AND 6TH FISHING CO-OP CHIEF
BU SANG-GIL
Are we ever getting any meat?
Are you saving it up or something?
Why would you come all the way
just to be grumpy?
A predecessor would never miss
an inauguration ceremony.
I'm the former king who's here to check
on a nobody who knows jack shit.
You came because you'd look petty
if you didn't.
I've resigned.
I stepped down myself.
You know the 80-year-old grandpa
who owns the variety shop?
He hardly ever says anything,
but he asked if I knew about Sang-gil
massaging the real estate agent's feet.
Come on! She had toe cramps!
I had to save the person first!
Looks like I'll have to serve
my chief daughter-in-law for life.
Thanks to her meddling,
the family's full of officials.
If she's the chief,
Gwan-sik's like a king consort.
That'd make me the queen mother, right?
My goodness, she is making a fuss again.
She's something else.
Her luck changed after meeting Gwan-sik.
You're bragging, aren't you?
Bragging?
On that note,
I hear your daughter-in-law plays cards.
Hey, that's…
Isn't the pajeon ready yet?
Our First Lady sure is busy.
Don't call him the First Lady.
Hey, why can't you take that apron off?
-Mom.
-What?
Make them bigger.
Damn it.
He's really pissing me off.
You like that your daughter-in-law
is the chief, but you also don't like it.
What's so funny?
I don't think I've seen you before.
-You know me?
-Chief Oh.
Yes, I'm coming!
Chief Oh is on her way!
-Oh my!
-Why are you so surprised?
Like you've never made me
work for you before?
Is this revenge?
You're taking your revenge on me, right?
Isn't there any respect around here?
Unbelievable.
How could you let the wife
of my predecessor make jeon here?
I'm telling you,
Bu Sang-gil was massaging her feet!
As you know, during election campaigns,
people bring up all sorts of things,
like how someone's great-grandfather
used to have a mistress and all that.
Like how I used to go dancing?
You never brought that up.
It wasn't my intention, but I feel like
I've caused a stir in your household.
But we took care of
the real estate woman ourselves.
I couldn't care less.
Gyeong-suk from the salon
and Mi-suk from the real estate office.
On this tiny island,
there are so many women
with such poor taste in men.
Well, I guess the worst of them
is me, Park Yeong-ran.
Anyway, you should go.
Some people just gossip
for no good reason.
Do you think they'll say
I have no dignity?
No, but I feel kind of sorry
that you're making jeon for us.
I have a reason to be here.
I have every right to be here.
I voted for you,
so I think I should be able to enjoy
a drink you provide.
Yeong-ran.
When you go home,
no, for the rest of your life,
tell your husband
that you voted for him, okay?
Hey, Park Yeong-ran!
I'm asking who you voted for!
Why can't you answer me?
You didn't vote for me, did you?
Is Mom the easiest target in the world?
Hey, you little brat.
Are you disrespecting me?
What do you know?
You don't even know a damn thing.
Why?
Why did the governor attend?
Why did he come
to the co-op chief's inauguration?
He didn't come to mine.
The governor came?
It was the governor who presented Gwan-sik
with the plaque of appreciation.
A person who jumped into the water?
If I saw them,
I would save them countless times too.
I'd receive a commendation!
That thing about the reward?
And he's sending them on a trip too?
The governor likes Gwan-sik.
He's very fond of him.
Of course he likes Gwan-sik.
I'm sure he does.
Why?
Why does everyone like Yang Gwan-sik?
GOVERNOR HWANG IN-SU
CONGRATULATIONS ON YOUR INAUGURATION
If your grandmother were here,
she would've thrown a box of red beans.
What the hell are you doing?
Hey!
Come here!
You fool!
You're so embarrassing.
You gotta stop her.
She's really getting out of hand.
Man, she really loves Busan.
She always calls herself Literary Girl.
You're no bookworm! You're just a worm!
Look, she's dancing with the pole.
Throw red beans at her! Throw them!
Father!
Let her be. Let her have her fun.
It's a good thing I started raising you.
Let's go, my good boy.
Where's Goldie?
Come on, my Goldie.
Oh dear, let's go home, my good boy.
Father.
I'll carry her.
Are you that happy?
Yeah.
I'm happy.
I'm so happy.
You're not a runner-up, a vice president,
or a deputy chief anymore.
You really are a chief.
But you know,
I finally got rid of the "deputy"
in my title after 30 years,
but the person I want to tell the most
isn't here.
My childhood was so difficult
that I never missed it.
But if I was asked to go back…
I'd do it all over again.
Just so I could hold
my mom's hand again.
Actually, the reason
I'm the vice president and a runner-up now
is because I wanna be the chief one day.
Even with diving,
you start in shallow waters
before moving to deeper ones.
I'll gain experience little by little
and become a chief one day.
No one can beat a chief.
Even Auntie Gyeong-ja
repays her loans to the chief.
Okay, you be the chief one day
so I can be the chief's mother.
Prepare enough rice cakes that day.
I'm going to make so many rice cakes
that they'll pile up like that mountain.
-Because you'd be happy?
-Yes, I'd be happy.
I'd be happy too.
I'm holding back
because I want to express
my happiness that day.
I'm not going to hold back.
Every time I'm really happy,
I'll let everyone know.
Why hold back?
Aunties, make sure
you take double portions, all right?
Goodness me.
You all fed and raised me
with these red-ribboned nets.
Now go around and brag about me
on my mom's behalf.
Honestly.
You must've used a ton of rice.
Why did you make so many rice cakes?
Apparently, this is from our Gwang-rye!
Oh dear.
Gwang-rye!
Your daughter is all grown up.
She's the chief now.
She was only ten when she sat
on this very floor in mourning clothes.
Back then,
I wondered whether she'd make it.
Who knew she would not only survive
but also thrive?
If Gwang-rye were still with us,
she would have taken a drum
and played it all around Hallasan.
You dug into the frozen ground
with your tiny hands
and buried your heart in it.
This must be your harvest season at last.
Gwang-rye's persimmon tree is fruitful.
So fruitful!
Indeed,
it was fall, the season of harvest,
when all kinds of fruits were ripening.
Each one filled
with its own chaotic story.
Each one growing
under its own ray of sunlight.
Hey, look.
Why?
Sorry?
Why are you in the front seat again?
Just because
it's fun.
It really annoys her
when I do that.
That mean girl you told me about?
Yes.
Yeong-beom!
Yeong-beom.
Jjajangmyeon was all you wanted?
So you don't know that car either?
There's something really weird
about Yang Geum-myeong, right?
Stop saying weird things.
Not all poor people lack class.
Ye-rim, stop taking her side.
She's always mean to you,
so why are you always so nice to her?
It's because her mind is twisted.
I can understand her.
What do you mean she's twisted?
My dad and I had a little talk
about Geum-myeong.
He said those who rise from nothing
often get twisted.
She must've been the best
in her tiny town.
But it's different here,
so her mind must be twisted.
She feels more inferior every day.
Dad says the better person
should let it go.
That's what class is.
But…
why would she be like that?
Her GPA is higher than yours.
By 0.2. Just a 0.2 difference.
-She's taller too.
-By 2 cm?
And…
You must remember everything about her.
-What else?
-Anyway…
Don't "anyway" me. What else?
Anyway, Geum-myeong was
the first chosen to go to Japan.
If she hadn't given it up,
you wouldn't be going, but thanks to her--
If I were a professor,
I would have chosen her too.
My family can afford to send me abroad.
Naturally, the school would support
a less fortunate girl.
Ye-rim.
Geum-myeong's family is doing well.
-Her father's a boat captain.
-He's a fisherman.
Birds of a feather flock together!
You sure are classy.
I'm not gonna eat.
She dumped you, didn't she?
What's with that foreign car? Tell me!
You're just dying to know, aren't you?
PRIVATE TUTORING BAN SPARKS ODDITIES
TUTORING EVEN TAKING PLACE IN MOVING CARS!
23RD TYPHOON "PHYLLIS"
CAUTIONS IN FISHING TOWNS
Will the waves be safe today?
Regardless of whether the waves are safe,
my dad still takes his boat out.
I'm the only one
who always worries about him.
-I'll see you guys.
-Bye.
Okay, let's go!
Speak with respect!
"Shut the fuck"? Jesus Christ.
You can't even spell "Wednesday."
Where'd you learn to curse?
Jenny, can you spell "Wednesday" now?
-Write it down here. Now.
-Don't.
Why is your name even Oh Jenny?
I was scared you were from overseas.
Anyone else would've been fired by now.
Not just fired but--
Just fire me already.
Actually, why don't you fire me?
I heard no other tutor lasted a month.
Well, look forward to it.
Put your feet down!
Seriously!
Hey, Oh Jammy. You didn't memorize
the vocabulary, did you?
You just come here to eat, don't you?
I think your housekeeper can cook dishes
from all over the country.
She said these glass noodles
are from Busan.
That lady always uses
other people's money to gain favor.
You're such a brat
that she might quit here soon too.
She's been here the longest.
Mom keeps her for some reason.
People don't stay at your house
for very long, do they?
Why?
Come on, why?
Well,
why haven't I ever met
your mother and father?
But that's better, isn't it?
Well, I'd like to see their faces
at least once.
Mom saw you. Just not at home.
Your mom saw me?
Where?
You had your picture on your résumé.
Just fill the time and go.
Honestly, you're here for the jar,
not 'cause you like me.
For you, it's love-hate.
For the jar, it's pure love.
Can you do something about your bangs
and how you part your hair?
You don't look like you're from Seoul!
Why are you so interested in my hairstyle?
I mean, do you and I really look alike?
What?
I'm the sexier one, right?
"Sexy"? Did you just say sexy?
Hey!
Spell "sexy" right here. Spell it.
I can spell that one. S-E--
Stop it.
-S-E!
-Stop it!
Is that all you're interested in?
How dare you. Seriously.
Mom said take what you earned.
No more, no less.
Your mother always puts me
to the test every single time.
Hello? Yeah, what?
Just grab a handful.
Charge double for a dumb student.
What is it?
My mom's coming up. She wants to see you.
-What? Right now?
-Just go.
I said just go.
Ms. Yang.
That's real white porcelain.
I have everything now.
I even have white porcelain
and blue porcelain at home.
The one thing we don't have
is a good education.
I see.
I deeply regret
the limited education I had.
I wanted to live vicariously
through my child,
but sadly, she inherited my intellect.
We'll improve her grades gradually.
We can't afford to wait
for them to improve gradually.
Life doesn't wait for anyone, does it?
I see.
Are you saying I should stop coming…
Jenny is rich,
but she doesn't have the brains.
You earned your way through school,
but you're smart.
I'm saying we should share what we have.
I'll give you an ace
so you can hit a blackjack.
It took us two years to find a tutor
who looked like Jenny.
I won't beat around the bush.
Ms. Yang.
Please take her college entrance exam.
STUDENT ID
OH JENNY
If she gets into
one of the top three universities,
I'll buy you
a three-bed apartment in Seoul.
For anything less, a two-bed instead.
NOTICE
LIST OF APPROVED APPLICANTS FOR DORMS
If a name isn't on the list,
can't they live in the dorms?
No.
I wonder how much the rent is
for boarding houses here.
It's expensive.
It'll be expensive.
Is he picking a fight or what?
The day of this historic election,
December 16th, is upon us,
with the eyes of the world closely on us.
It's been 16 years
since we last voted freely for president.
The atmosphere was solemn and serious.
They say dorm assignments
are drawn at random,
but I think something is fishy.
Apparently, South Korea is one
of the most corrupt countries.
So, who are you voting for?
I think we need to call
the military police to take him.
-What?
-Why is a soldier near the girls' dorm?
The guys' dorms are nearby.
They come and go while on their leave.
Who did you vote for?
Can we get him locked up in the brig?
One, two, three.
Hello, Father!
Well, we met once
at the admission ceremony.
My name is Park Yeong-beom.
I'm a friend of Geum-myeong.
I also took a few pictures
of your family that day, and…
So, you must have taken a plane
and then a bus to see Geum-myeong.
So why?
-Sir?
-Why would you call me "Father"?
-Sorry?
-You said, "Hello, Father."
Why did you call me "Father"?
For what reason?
TEST IDENTIFICATION SLIP
OH JENNY
Dear me.
Oh dear.
Ma'am, we could get into
serious trouble doing this.
Tutoring is already illegal,
so my heart races every time I come here.
Your heart needs to race
to make some money.
There's no jackpot
if you don't bet on anything.
If I got caught, I'd be expelled.
Exactly, the high risk of expulsion
is why you'd get an apartment.
The exam isn't a joke.
How could I ever be Jenny?
Whoever the proctor is,
I will offer them a bribe.
I'll have everything set up perfectly
so you won't have to worry about a thing.
You earn money
by doing what you're good at.
I'll support you
by doing what I'm good at.
Isn't it fair, proper, and profitable
to earn a living
by doing what you're good at?
Just take the plunge this once
and grab the ace.
Ma'am, the thing is--
No.
I don't want your answer now.
Think carefully.
Think very carefully before you speak.
You didn't get a scholarship,
and you have to leave the dorms, right?
Are you really giving up
on studying abroad?
How do you know all that?
Like I said, think carefully.
Don't just think about yourself.
Think of your parents
who work so hard for you.
For a dragon to really rise from a stream,
the stream has to dry up, right?
Come with me.
Hey! Go to your room.
Young lady!
Young lady! Wait up!
Goodness me.
Did you come out of unit 908?
Sorry? Why did you…
If you run,
I can't catch up with you.
Why would I run?
You stole something from there, no?
Sorry?
Just give it here.
Let's not make this any worse.
Is that what that lady said?
I don't want to hear your answer now.
Just take these with you.
Look at them two or three times
or even more.
Then we'll talk again.
Frankly, trying to rise as a dragon
from a stream is selfish, you know?
You'd think the dragon
would give back to its parents,
but just think about it.
Your father is still on that boat
because of you.
And he'll stay on that boat
for the rest of his life.
My father also trusted his eldest son,
who said he'd take the bar exam,
and he fed his cows until the day he died.
If I think of my mom and dad,
there's nothing more for me to ponder.
It'd be great for me to earn an apartment
by doing what I'm good at.
Yes. I like that you're so frank.
But thinking of my mom and dad,
I can't do it.
What?
I was taught to be the last in my class
rather than cheat.
I was taught not to even pick up
a ten-won coin at the playground.
My mom and dad would never approve
of me living life shamelessly.
Are you trying to tell me something?
Also,
if I take the test for Jenny
and she happens to get accepted,
another girl like me won't make it.
I can't bear the thought
of a girl like me not making it
because of a fraud.
She'd die of heartbreak.
Ms. Yang Geum-myeong.
When you have resources and act nobly,
you are seen as a person of integrity.
But when a poor girl pretends to be noble,
it's deemed reckless courage.
Sending a girl who can't spell "Wednesday"
to a top-three school would be reckless--
-Reckless courage.
-Hey!
Let Jenny find her path
by doing what she's good at.
Isn't that fair, proper,
and profitable for Jenny?
Yeah, I want to be a singer.
I'll be going now.
This is why I hate
people who rise from nothing.
You have absolutely nothing,
yet pride is all you have to show off!
Dumb and rude, so it should be quadruple.
I'll take my extra pay, then.
I'm not a thief.
I know. It's not fear
that makes people avoid her.
It’s my money,
but I'll give it up just to avoid them.
And the ring?
Sorry?
Diamond. The diamond ring.
They wished every day
that the world beyond their embrace
would always be gentle.
Ma'am!
Hey! Oh Jammy!
Hey, open the door!
Hey! Why am I a thief? Why?
But the world away from their embrace
was a jungle.
"IN THE HOPE THAT OUR ECHOES
WILL FLOW AND FLOW, UNTIL THEY REACH YOU."
Subtitle translation by: Sung In Jang